Nothing spreads like fear.
Contagion is a drama, thriller, science fiction
film directed by Steven Soderbergh.
As an epidemic of a lethal airborne virus - that kills within days - rapidly grows, the worldwide medical
community races to find a cure and control the panic that spreads faster than the virus itself.
Leonora Orantes, played by Marion Cotillard.
Mitch Emhoff, played by Matt Damon.
Ellis Cheever, played by Laurence Fishburne.
Alan Krumwiede, played by Jude Law.
Erin Mears, played by Kate Winslet.
Ally Hextall, played by Jennifer Ehle.
Contagion is a 2011 American medical thriller
film directed by Steven Soderbergh.
Its ensemble cast includes Matt Damon, Laurence Fishburne, Jude Law,
Marion Cotillard, Kate Winslet, and Gwyneth Paltrow.
The plot concerns the spread of a highly contagious virus transmitted through respiratory droplets and fomites, attempts by medical researchers and public health officials to
identify and contain the disease, the loss of social order as the virus turns into a worldwide pandemic, and the introduction of a vaccine to halt its spread.
To follow several interacting plot lines, the film makes use of the multi-narrative
"hyperlink cinema" style, popularized in several of Soderbergh's films.
The film was inspired by real-life outbreaks such as the
2002–2004 SARS outbreak and the 2009 flu pandemic.
Following their collaboration on The Informant!
(2009), Soderbergh and screenwriter Scott Z.
Burns discussed a film depicting the rapid spread of a virus.
Burns consulted with representatives of the World Health
Organization as well as medical experts such as W.
Ian Lipkin and Larry Brilliant.
Principal photography started in Hong Kong in September 2010, and continued in Chicago,
Atlanta, London, Dublin, Geneva, and San Francisco Bay Area until February 2011.
Contagion premiered at the 68th Venice International Film Festival on September
3, 2011, and was theatrically released on September 9, 2011.
Commercially, the film made $136.5 million against
its $60 million production budget.
Critics praised it for its narrative and the
performances, as did scientists for its accuracy.
The film received renewed popularity in 2020 due to
the emergence of the COVID-19 pandemic.
The film explores themes of quarantine, saving the world,
mutation, infection, terminal illness.
The tone is emotional and thought_provoking and intense.